你还好不?
you okay?
我在想办法
I'm thinking.
光想可不能助你登顶
Thinking's not gonna get youto the top.
妈妈 你不是该鼓励我嘛
Mom,you're supposed to beencouraging me.
不 我该指导你
No,I'm supposedto be coaching you.****
你左上方一尺距离 有个踏点
there's a hold about a/foot above you on the left.
我知道
I know.
抓得好
Nice grab.
继续 你快到了 宝贝
Keep going,you're almost there,babe.
不行了 我小腿抽筋
I can't. My calf's cramping.
你得放松脚趾
You need to get off your toes.
用脚掌踏
Get on the ball of your foot.
- 我做不到/- 不 你可以的
- I can't./- Yes,you can.
你可以一路登顶的
You can get all the way to the top.
没事 我稳住你了 你没事吧?
It's okay,I got you.You all right?
看来你预计错了
Looks like you were wrong.
是啊 但你做得不错
Yeah,but you did awesome.
这是你攀过的最高高度了
That's the highest you've gotten.
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
我不太舒服
I don't feel so good.
那好 下来吧
Okay,come on down.
妈妈?
Mom?
妈 你没事吧?
Mom,are you okay?
哦 没事
Oh,god.
你还好吗?
are you all right?
我的手臂...可能摔断了
My arm...I think I broke it.
- 别动/- 天 Jane 太抱歉了
- Don't move./- God,jane,I'm so sorry.
怎么回事? 绳子断了吗?
What happened?Did the rope break?
不是 我的手
No.My hands...
动不了了
I can't move them.
她接受过整形医生 两位神经科医生/和免疫学家的治疗
She's been to an ortho,two/neuros,and an immunologist.
以上治疗都没任何后遗症
None of the treatments/have had any effect.
你觉得 这事结束了吗?
You think it's over?
越来越糟了
It's getting worse.
上次检查中 不止双手麻痹/神经科医生还发现她双臂间歇性麻木
Last neurologist found intermittent numbness/in both arms as well as the hand paralysis.
我说这游戏
I meant the game.
你觉得 他会留下我们所有四个?
You think he's gonna/keep all four of us?
他说会的
He said he would.
没有上运动神经元损害的迹象
No sign of upper motor/neuron involvement.
他谎话连篇
He lies.
我耳朵烫死啦
My ears are burning.
告诉他们 你不再炒人了
Tell 'em you're done firing people.
如果我爱撒谎...
Well,if I lie...
这么说也没法叫人安心
that would be  little reassurance.
Kutner医生 谁让你在这虚伪的时节/用这些肤浅的装饰
Dr. Kutner,who told you that it would be a good idea to/put up superficial representations of a hypocritical season
欢庆一个虚构的人?
celebrating a mythical figure?
不是我干的
It wasn't me.
他谎话连篇
He lied.
居家先生深谙其道
Homey knows better,
犹太先生漠不关心/亨廷顿小姐本可以做得更好
hymie doesn't care, and huntington's/would have done a better job.
我没得亨廷顿病
I don't have huntington's.
是你不自知
that you know of.
- 你为啥不.../- 因为我叫你"软蛋" 却被投诉了
- Why would you.../- because I got sued when I called you "honeybuns."
我挂些装饰 就要被解雇了吗...
Am I fired if I put up...
这游戏的目的就是想吓唬我们
the point of the game was to scare us.
告诉我们结束了 可不吓人
Telling us it's over isn't scary.
所以 他说的应该是真话
Therefore he has no reason/to say that unless it's true.
那就好
Good.
那我们玩神秘圣诞老人游戏吧?
Then can we do a secret santa?
我还是喜欢你15秒前 害怕丢了工作的样子
I liked you better 15 seconds ago/when you were afraid for your job.
谁病了?
So who's sick?
35岁的单身妈妈
35-year-old/single mom.
奇怪的麻痹症状
It's an odd presentation  of paralysis.
有吸毒史吗?
Is there any history of drug use?
没有
No.
她自己说 无吸毒史
She says  there's no history.
她可不是骗子
She's not a liar.
这下好了 这病例难了
Okay,this is gonna be a tough case.
我不懂外星人生理学啊
I have almost no knowledge/of alien physiology.
人人都会撒谎 没错/但是每条定理都有例外
Everyone lies,but there's/an exception to every rule.
其实没有
Actually,there isn't.
这也是条定理
That's kinda what makes it a rule.
病人的母亲在她7岁时 死于乳癌
The patient's mother died of/breast cancer when she was seven.
她甚至不知道她妈有病
She never even knew her mom was sick.
于是她对自己发誓/她绝不会对自己的女儿有所保留
She promised herself she would never/hide anything from her own daughter.
哦 我不知道她发誓了
Oh,I didn't know she promised.
我们不是她女儿
And we're not her daughter.
病人从她妈那遗传得了/乳腺癌BRCA1变异基因
The patient inherited the/brca1 mutation from her mom.
10年前 她做了预防性双侧乳腺切除术
She got a prophylactic double/mastectomy ten years ago.
她撒谎了
She lied about it.
她告诉了她的同事
She told her co-workers.
告诉了她女儿
She told her kid.
她欺骗了全世界
She lied to the world.
重建手术就是让人相信...
Reconstructive surgery is/designed to convince people...
她没做重建手术
she didn't get reconstructive surgery.
好吧 我们能排除乳癌可能了
okay,we can rule out  breast cancer.
其实 我正要将之考虑在内呢
Actually,I was gonna rule it in.
麻痹可能是副肿瘤性的
Paralysis could be paraneoplastic.
即使最棒的外科医生/也不能移除她所有乳腺组织细胞
Even the best surgeon can't/remove every cell of breast tissue.
做个核磁共振 看看她的胸还剩了点啥
Mri what's left of her chest.
也让那机器查查有没有口是心非
Set the machine to scan for irony.
我重新调查病史去
I'm gonna go redo the patient history.
你妈告诉你 她都吸啥毒品了没?
Your mom tell you about/all the drugs she does?
她偶尔吸大麻 但吸食不久
She smokes pot once in a/while,but not in a long time.
那你呢?
What about you?
这怎么会使她致病呢?
How would that make her sick?
你是医生吗?
Are you a doctor?
我才11岁
I'm 11.
这不算回答
That's not an answer.
这是回避
That's an evasion.
喝酒不?
Like drinking?
你有没偷喝过酒?
You ever sneak a drink?
我可没这些坏毛病
I don't do any of that stuff.
对人身心不益
It's bad for you.
我理解 你为啥不想让你妈知道
I understand why you don't/want your mom to know.
- 但我是她医生 所以.../- 我会告诉我妈
- But I'm her doctor,so.../- I would tell my mom.
我也会告诉你
And I would tell you.
为什么?
Why?
因为她从不骗我
Because she would never lie to me.
她最爱的做爱姿势是?
What's her favorite way to have sex?
我不明白 做爱和乳癌有啥关系
I don't get what sex has/to do with breast cancer.
你是医生吗?
Are you a doctor?
我前次问你后 你就上医学院去了吗?
Did you go to med school/since the last time I asked?
你以为我们一定会对医生撒...
You just think we've/got to be lying to...
善意的谎言?
white lies?
什么意思?
What are those?
那是我们为安慰别人 撒的谎
Those are lies we tell to/make other people feel better.
我从不撒谎
I don't lie.
自欺欺人?
Rationalizations?
这又是啥?
What are those?
是安慰自己 撒的谎
Those are lies we tell to/make ourselves feel better.
- 我们不.../- 遮遮掩掩的谎话?
- We don't/- Lies of omission?
骑乘野马还是狗趴式?
Saddle bronc or doggie?
那是性爱术语
That's sex talk.
她过去喜欢自己在上的体位
She used to like being on top.
但现在她喜欢俯卧着
But now she likes to be on her stomach.
那样 她就不必看见他们盯着她的疤痕了
That way she doesn't have to/see them looking at her scars.
那是虐待儿童啊
It's child abuse.
因为她坦诚?
Honesty?
人人撒谎不是没道理的...撒谎有用啊
There's a reason that/everybody lies... it works.
它能推动社会运转
It's what allows society to function.
它将人类和禽兽区分开
It's what separates man from beast.
哦 我还以为是大拇指的功能呢
Oh,I thought that was our thumbs.
你想知道 你妈的拇指都碰过啥了?
You wanna know every place/your mom's thumb has been?
抱歉 我错过"预演"了
I'm sorry,I missed rehearsal.
我不是该坚持"人应该坦诚"的观点吗?
Am I taking the "truth is good" side?
难道平时是你持这个观点啊?
Don't you usually take that part?
撒谎的目的可能是善意...
Lies are a tool to be/used either for good...
不 等等 我想到个更好的
no,wait.I got a better one.
谎言犹如孩童
Lies are like children.
培养不易 但他们值得/因为未来靠他们建设
Hard work,but they're worth/it,because the future depends on 'em.
你真是心中充满爱啊...
You are so full of love...
还是啥的
or something.
- 当你在乎某人.../- 你就对他们撒谎!
- When you care about someone.../- you lie to them!
你假装觉得他们固执乏味的思想是有趣的
You pretend that their constant/ponderous musings are interesting.
你告诉他们/他们不会失去孩子般的漂亮面孔
You tell them that they're not/losing their boyish good looks
不会苍老...
or becoming worn out and...
我修改立场
I stand corrected.
请允许我说/和你聊天 真是愉快啊
And may I say it's been a real/pleasure chatting with you.
腋窝没问题
Axilla's clean.
手术切缘很清晰
Surgical margins look clear.
没有淋巴结病 没有肿块 啥也没有
No lymphadenopathy,no masses,no nothing.
不是癌症
It's not cancer.
咱得想个新推断了
we need a new theory.
你逮到她撒谎了?
You catch her lying?
还没
Not yet.
说"没有"不是更直截了当吗?
Wouldn't "no" have/been a shorter answer?
你闭嘴不说话 不是更简洁明了吗?
Wouldn't you not talking have/made this a shorter conversation?
小孩说 妈妈是个荡妇
Kid says mom's a slut.
她称她妈是荡妇?
She called her mom a slut?
我叫她妈荡妇
No,I called her mom a slut.
她见谁都能勾搭上
She jumps anything/with a pole and a pulse.
不是我对她有偏见啊
Not that I'm judging here.
从她的病历看 我吃惊不小呢
Given her medical history,I'm/actually impressed.
Maggie已承认她有多个性伴侣
Maggie already admitted tohaving/multiple sexual partners,symptoms.
所以我们才已做完检测/排除了梅毒或其他可致其症状的性病
which is why we alreadytested for and ruled out/syphilisand any other std that could have causedher
性病并非是不安全性爱的唯一风险
Stds aren't the only riskin risky sex.
和陌生人上床的问题就是/他们是陌生的
The problem in sleeping with/strangers is they're strange.
我们去调查她最近的性伴侣
We'll follow upwith any recent partners.
让Foreman和Taub去吧
Send foreman and taub.
他们更会撒谎
They're better liars.
更可能获知真相
More likely to getto the truth.
你们认为 我给她下了药?
you think I drugged her?
用茶杯垫好吧
Use a coaster.
我们又不是警察
We're not cops.
法律上讲 你们无论怎样 我们都不管
Legally,we don't careone way or another.
但我们得知道真相 才能帮助她
But we need to know the/truthso we can help her.
我和她认识一个小时不到/她就提出带我回家
I'd known herfor less than an/hour,and she offeredto take me home.
根本没必要给她下药
There was no needto drug her.
我也不会给人下药
Not that i would.
她会没事的吧?
She's gonna be okay,right?
她恐怕是没法拾起或握紧东西了
As long as she doesn't have to/pick up or hold anything.
抱歉 我刚弄好地板呢
Sorry,I just had the floors done.
新生松木
Reclaimed pine.
你一直那么渴吗?
You always this thirsty?
我不知道
I don't know.
喝水有益健康 不是吗?
Water's supposed to/begood for you,right?
脱水 焦躁 盛气凌人...
Dehydration,anxiety,aggression...
我没有盛气凌人啊
I'm not aggressive.
右手有痉挛性舞蹈症
Spastic choreain his right hand.
我手怎么了?
What about my hand?
你多重? 180 190磅左右?
How much you weigh?About 180,190?
180 这有什么关...
180.What is the...
如果你俩服用了一种药物/不久也可能出现同样病症
if you took what she did,it/could take longer to hit you.
它对你俩的影响可能不同
It might affect you differently.
但你没有给她吃什么...是吧?
But you didn't give heranything...right?
她那时已醉得厉害
She was really drunk.
我只是给了她点迷幻药 保持她的兴奋
I just gave her some "e"/to help enhance things.
那东西还有没有剩?
Have any of it left?
我的手没事吧?
Is my hand gonna be okay?
啥事也没
there's nothing wrong with it.
我们骗你的
We lied.
我喉咙痛了好几天了
I've had a sore/throat for a few days now.
肚子也不舒服
My stomach's also been bothering me.
我觉得是扁桃体腺肿了
I think my glandsare swollen.
圣-尼古拉吗?(即圣诞老人)
Saint nicholas?
孩子们的守护神
Patron saint of children.
还是海员 商人 弓箭手 妓女/和囚犯的守护神呢
Also seamen,merchants,archers,prostitutes,and/prisoners.
他的工作很辛苦
M,must've been pretty hard-working.
或者是他把好事都往身上揽
Or just a credit hog.
嘴张大
Open wide.
说"啊"
Say ahh.
啊...
Ahh...
你有链锁状球菌
you have strep.
会传染不?
Is it contagious?
只要你服了抗生素/那24小时后就不会传染
Only for the next 24 hours,as/long as you take the antibiotics.
传染性有多严重?
How contagious?
请假吧
Take a personal day.
那可不行
I can't.
我给开个假条给你交给妈妈桑
I'll write your pimpa note.
什么妈妈桑?
My pimp?
你每三个月做一次爱滋病检查/而你项链的式样
You're tested for aids every/three months,and your necklace.
是妓女都爱带宗教标志的项链
Prostitutes wear religious symbols.
我想是因为她们喜欢下跪
I think they just like kneeling.
你皮肤这么好不可能 是水手
You don't have the skin of a seaman,
手指不像是弓箭手的 穿得不像商人/态度也不像是蹲过号子的
the fingers of an archer,the clothes of/a merchant,or the attitude of an ex-con.
所以只剩这一个可能了
So it just leavesone left.
应该是两个
Two,actually.
但我显然不是小孩 对吧?
But I'm not a child,am I?
宝贝 给我你的爱
Well,give me your love,baby
你欠我50块
you owe me 50 bucks.
你欠我半个脱衣舞
Then you owe me half a lap dance.
是给护士凑圣诞红利
It's for the nurses'holiday bonus.
我留便条告诉你了
I know you got the memo.
去年我不也收到了
I got the memo last year.
我还要再雇40个人
I want to hire 40 more fellows.
你刚雇的人又要炒掉啦?
You already fired the ones you hired?
他们感到威胁的时候干得更好些
They work better when they're scared.
你是对的 那男的给她下了迷幻药
You were right. Guy slipped her ecstasy.
他自己有没有症状?
He have any symptoms?
没有
No.
Kutner在给病人进行血液透析
Kutner's starting the/patient on hemodialysis,
13号化验那男人在药里放了什么
and thirteen's in the lab trying to/figure out what the guy put in the drugs.
看到没?
See?
清楚明了地证明了他们通力合作/对我既无敌意也不畏惧
A clear,simple statement of facts describing/their cooperation with absolutely no attitude or fear.
所以你非做点什么不可了
Something's gotta be done.
那是
Oh,yeah.
感觉如何?
How are you feeling?
手还是动不了
I still can't move my hands.
让你全部血液都透析一遍还需要几个小时
It'll take a few more hours  to cycle/all your blood through the machine.
发生什么事了?
What just happened?
没事啊 怎么了?
Nothing.What's wrong?
你说什么 灯一下全黑了
What do you mean?The/lights just went out.
不是么?
Didn't they?
你做了些什么?
What did you do?
是药物造成的么?
Is this from the drugs?
大部分的药物应该都已经排出了啊
Most of the drugs should/be out of your system by now.
- 而我们给的也不应该.../- 我看不见了
- And our drugs.../- I can't see.
做些什么啊
Do something.
我看不见了
I can't see.
我看不见了!
I can't see!
迷幻药里是单纯的迷幻药
Nothing in the ecstasy except ecstasy.
不会对人造成伤害
Well,that never hurt anybody.
不可能让人在几天后双目失明
It can't make 'em blind days later.
居家先生的居你怎么写?
Do you spell "homie"with a "y"?
保险起见问一下
I want to be respectful.
你真的要我们玩神密圣诞老人游戏?
You're actually gonna/let us do secret santa?
不止你们
Not just you guys.
我也想要礼物
I like presents too.
抽一个名字
Pick a name.
你为什么这么做?
Why are you doing this?
看 这就是为什么大家都讨厌你这些人
See,this is why no one likes your people.
一年中选一个特定的时间
The notion of picking/one time of the year
对他人友善的想法简直恶心
to be decent to other people is obscene,
因为它恰恰使人感到在别的时候/做个废物是顺理成章的
'cause it's actually validating the notion of/being miserable wretches the rest of the year.
所以你正是要挑这个时间来搞怪?
So you think this is the part/of the year that's screwed up?
另一方面来说 大家现在是个团队
On the other hand,you are now a team.
要共事
You've gotta work together.
互赠破玩意儿能增进感情
And the simple fact is,giving/people crap makes people like people.
就花个25块 体验一下爱的感觉吧
So spend 25 bucks.Learn to love.
失明很可能是血液透析造成的
Blindness could be a complication/from the hemodialysis.
不 透析液成分是掌握好的
No,the dialysate/composition was within range.
这下可好
Sweet.
有意思
Interesting.
- 透析液的成分可能会.../- 不是那个
- Dialysate composition just indicates.../- nothing.
有意思的是他看到名字后的反应
I was referring to his/reaction to the name he got.
我很高兴 我觉得买礼物给...
I was pleased.I thought/it would be fun to buy...
说明我们中某人是让人不想送礼物给他的
means there's someone here/it wouldn't be fun to buy for.
我在猜那是谁
I wonder who.
随便挑一个
Pick a name.
去查查病人家里的情况
Then go check out the patient's house.
真是有意思
Interesting.
去她家是浪费时间
we're wasting time going to the home.
克恩-塞尔综合症符合所有的症状/(线粒体脑肌病)
Kearns-sayre syndrome fits the symptoms.
没有家族病史 去她们家
No family history of/kearns.Go to their house...
如果家里有别的药物 她会告诉我们的
she would have told us if/there were any other drugs.
你见过她的 难道她还不够坦诚么
You met her.She couldn't/have been more candid.
我完全同意
You're absolutely right.
去她们家
Go to their house...
多发性硬化或血管问题更符合症状/可能影响到手部和眼睛
ms or vascular problem fits/better.They could affect hands and eyes.
好 做核磁共振查是不是多发性硬化
Fine,do an mri,check for ms.
还有眼底萤光造影检查/看看有没有出血
And a fluorescein angiogram of her eyes/to see if we missed a bleed somewhere.
还有去她家的人
Oh,and whoever goes to their house,
给我把电脑带回来
get me their computers.
大人和小孩谈谈性问题/就让孩子以为一切都开诚布公
You talk to your kid about sex  so she'll/think you're being open about everything.
这样孩子就不会问那些/他们不想回答的问题了
Keeps her from asking questions about/the things you don't want to talk about.
说得好啊
That's right.
她的诚实恰好证明了她的不诚实
Her honesty proves just/how dishonest she is.
太好啦
Yes!
我就想要抽到他
Exactly who I wanted.
这下好玩了
This is gonna be fun.
染料进入你血管的时候可能会有点疼
The dye may sting when it/enters your bloodstream.
你害怕么 妈妈?
Are you scared,mom?
是啊
Yeah.
你呢?
Are you?
也怕
Yeah.
他们呢?
Are they?
他们看起来不怕
They don't look scared.
要不是他们有信心 就是他们不在乎
Either they're confident or/they just don't care.
我们有信心
We're confident.
请移动一下
Okay if I shift you a bit?
位置调整好
Get you into position.
你们老大是个怪人
Your boss is weird.
是啊
Yeah,he is.
他为了让你们说出不想说的 就得...
He thought he'd get information you/may not have been telling us by...
做个混蛋?
being a jerk?
你们一定不信 他通常得手
You'd be surprised how often it works.
脉络膜看上去没问题
Choroidal flush looks good.
人们为什么要向医生撒谎?
Why would people lie to a doctor?
撒谎的理由很多 说实话只有一个理由
Dozens of reasons to lie,only/one reason to tell the truth.
你没有想过撒谎?
you're never even tempted?
我是说 有些谎言确实能息事宁人/让日子好过一点
I mean,lies do sometimes smooth/things out,make life easier.
是么?
Yeah?
你的日子很好过?
Your life easy?
差得远了
Not even close.
染料已经到达视网膜毛细血管网了
The dye has reached the/retinal capillary bed.
没有渗漏
No leakage.
那是好事 对吧?
That's good,right?
说明不是血管问题
It means it's not a vascular problem.
什么?
what?
血管问题是可以医治的
A vascular problem we could fix.
他们现在看起来在担心了 妈妈
They look worried now,mom.
秘密圣诞老人这是在搞什么
What's with the secret santa?
你在设法让大家团结?
You trying to bring them together?
我在设法让大家分裂
I want to drive them apart.
用互赠礼物的方法?
With gift giving?
你听这充满矛盾的名字就知道了
Conflict's built right into the name.
圣诞老人应该是关于分享的
Santa's about shing.
而秘密又表示有所保留
A secret's about withholding.
除了特洛伊木马 通常礼物不会...
Aside from the trojan/horse,gifts don't usually...
最后一个结婚纪念日/你送你老婆什么礼物?
what'd you get your wife/for your final anniversary?
一件毛衣
Uh...a sweater.
她特别不喜欢吧
She hated it.
她很喜欢
She loved it.
那就说明不是你买的
Then you didn't buy it.
我给了她一些现金...
I gave her some cash...
然后
and...
礼物让我们清楚明白/我们有多么不了解别人
gifts allow us to demonstrate exactly/how little we know about a person.
没什么事情比被归类到/不属于自己的类型里更令人恼火了
And nothing pisses off a person more/than being shoved in the wrong pigeonhole.
是啊
Yes.
我想多花点钱买秘密圣诞老人的礼物
I'm thinking of spending a few/extra bucks on my secret santa.
不是个好想法
Bad idea.
你介意我告诉House你向母女俩/要了钥匙而不是硬闯空门么
You mind if I tell house you asked them/for the key instead of breaking in?
我介意/就多花个5块钱
Yes,I do.Just another five bucks.
你说5就是10
Five will be ten.
钥匙能说明她并没有隐藏什么
The key's proof she/doesn't have anything to hide.
钥匙说明我对House不是唯命是从
The key is proof I didn't do/exactly what house told me to do.
就多花15块 你有什么好在意的
And what do you care if it's another $15?
我要告诉他
I'm gonna tell him.
是谁让你这么想讨好的?
Who are you so anxious to please?
不是你
Not you.
你真要证明人性是诚实的
You really think you're going to/prove people are capable of honesty
用一对你只认识一天的母女作证据?
using a mother and/daughter you've known for one day?
我不会因为一件事撼动自己的世界观
I'm not the one who's based his/entire world view on the proposition.
就算错了又怎样?
If I'm wrong,so what?
而他错一次就不一样了
If he's wrong...
你有亨廷顿舞蹈病？
so you've got huntington's?
没
Nope.
- 但House说你.../- 如果我想谈这个 我会开口的
- But house said that you.../- if I wanted to talk about it,why didn't I bring it up?
眼底荧光血管造影没查出问题
fluorescein angiogram was clear.
没有渗漏或者外伤
No leaks,no lesions.
绝对不是血管问题
Definitely not a vascular problem.
谁帮我去文档里看看她们的生日是哪天
Someone get their/birthdays out of the file.
要不试试没有密码?
Have you tried leaving it blank?
完全信赖他人的人/想要看穿他们的想法很困难吧?
Tough to get into the head of someone/who actually trusts people,huh?
两台电脑是在她们共享的桌子上找到的
found both computers in an/office on a desk they share.
没有黄斑点变性或视神经炎
no sign of macular/degeneration or optic neuritis.
她的眼睛没有任何问题
Her eyes are completely normal.
除了看不见东西
Except she can't see out of them.
那也是她自己说的
So she says.
核磁共振发现什么了?
Find anything on the mri?
没看到粥样斑块 不是多发性硬化
No sign of plaques.It's not ms.
无论什么测试都没发现异常
We haven't found anything/abnormal on any test.
但她就是眼睛看不见 手不能动
Except she can't see or move her hands.
那也是她自己说的
So she says.
驰缓性麻痹这种事怎么装得了
You can't lie about flaccid paralysis.
也许说谎的不是她
Maybe she's not lying.
而是她的大脑
Her brain is.
如果这只是某种转换失调呢?
What if it's a conversion disorder?
缺少私人空间界限
Lacks personal boundaries...
滥交
promiscuous...
强迫自己要讲真话
inappropriate/obsession with truth telling.
听起来像是精神病病症
Certainly sounds like a psych case.
酷 让她开始心理指导和抗抑郁治疗
Cool,I'll set up a psych/consult,start her on anti-depressants.
不
No.
她的大脑给身体下了套
Her mind is tricking her body.
我们得给她的大脑下套
We need to trick her mind.
或者更绝的
Or even better.
你不需要她
You don't need her.
我知道
I know.
根本达不到医学上的目的
Then this serves no medical purpose.
你明明有遗传缺陷 你却不肯正视
You have a genetic/defect,choose to ignore it.
这女人有个遗传缺陷
This woman has a genetic defect.
她选择折磨自己来获得安全感
She chooses to butcher/herself to be safe.
你说你为她的诚实而着迷
Yet what you claimtoe/fascinated by is her honesty.
这很有趣
Interesting.
你说你向往真实
You claim to want the truth...
而你却给以讲求真实为生的人找麻烦
and then you screw with people/who actually live by it.
真可悲
Pathetic.
我还说你很有趣呢
I gave you credit for "interesting."
你维护她是因为她做了你做不到的事情
You're protecting her because you're/jealous she did what you couldn'T.
我需要你
I need you.
我不会对她说谎
I'm not lying to her.
好吧 你可以不说
Fine,keep your mouth shut.
但我还是需要你
I still need you.
如果最后不成功/你得帮忙安抚住那孩子
If it doesn't work,you/gotta hold the kid down
好让别人哄骗住母亲
until someone else finishes lying to mom.
真正是以治疗为目的
That does actually/serve a medical purpose.
Jane
Jane.
因为她信任我 所以我得跟她说谎?
I have to lie because she trusts me?
如果你表现出怀疑/安慰剂治疗就不会有效果
If you show doubt,the/placebo treatment won't work.
如果这只是单纯的抑郁症/那是好消息 对吧?
If it's just depression,that's/good news,right?
有很多很好的药物...
There are a lot of great medications.
那为什么不能直接就给她治疗?
Then why can't we just give her those?
为什么一定要骗她?
Why do we have to lie to her?
因为我们可能是错的
Because we might be wrong.
那些药物需要一定时间起作用
And those medications/take a long time to work,
而你妈妈的情况恶化得很快
and since you're mom's/condition is declining...
很有可能药物起效的时候已经太迟了
there's a chance the drugs won't/tell us anything until it's too late.
我妈妈没有抑郁
My mom's not depressed.
可能是她没有告诉你
Maybe she's hiding it from you.
不
No.
她不会的...
She wouldn't...
她和所有的好母亲一样
she's doing what every good mom does:
遇到束手无策的困境/不会告诉自己的孩子
Protecting her child from bad news/that she can't do anything about.
妈妈从没对我撒过谎
My mom's never lied to me.
如果你不会撒谎
If you don't know how to lie,
那你也不会知道 别人是否对你撒谎
you don't know how to/tell when you're being lied to.
也许你说的对
Maybe you're right.
- 我知道.../- 我撒谎了
- I know.../- I was lying.
我知道怎么撒谎
I know how to lie.
但我不会对妈妈那么做
I just won't do it to my mother.
喜欢玩桌上足球吗?
You like fooall?
要是不把你的感染性下肢轻瘫治好
Until the treatment of your/infectious paraparesis takes effect,
Jane就不能回到这个房间
jane can't come back into the room.
我已经接种疫苗了
I've already been inoculated.
她会不会已经感染了?
Can she have it already?
别担心 这药很有效
Don't worry,it's a/very effective treatment.
很快你就会感觉好转的
You should be feeling/better in a matter of minutes.
你不觉得Jane应该有些小秘密吗?
Don't you think jane/deserves a few secrets?
有些私人空间 才能...
Some personal space... room to,uh...
去经历一些错误?
make her own mistakes?
她犯过的错误多着呢
She makes plenty of mistakes.
但是我会帮助她走出来的
Only difference is I'm/there to help her through them.
可她知道你会在背后帮她
But she's gotta know/you're looking over her shoulder.
就像有了后盾...
It's gotta stifle...
我想那样的话世界会更美好一点
I think the world would be a better place
如果每个人都以为/妈妈会在背后支持自己
if everybody always acted like their/mom was looking over their shoulder.
我想去看妈妈
I want to go see my mom.
她在休息呢
She's sleeping.
不如我们把预算金额都翻番吧?
Why don't we just double the/amount we can spend?
不行
Nope.
舍不得多花二十五块?
Can't afford another $25?
如果允许的额度是五十块/那大家都会花六十块
If we allow people/$50,people will spend $60.
哦 是舍不得多花三十五块
Oh,so you can't afford another $35.
看来你相当喜欢自己抽到的那张签啊
You must really like who you got.
或者相当讨厌
Or really dislike.
妈妈总是把最好的礼物送给/最不喜欢我的老师
My mom always gives the best presents to/the teachers I get along with the worst.
- 不是的吧/- 不是的吧
- No./- No.
你们凭什么说不是?
How do you know "no"?
我知道你抽的肯定不是House
Know you didn't get house.
我知道他抽的不是House
I know he didn't get house.
你写的全都是你自己的名字?
you gave them all your name?
估计我会激起一些纠纷/还能收到领带和毛衣
Figured I could sow some dissention/and get a few ties and sweaters.
万一他们发现了怎么办?
What happens when they find out?
这是神密圣诞老人游戏
It's secret santa.
那万一他们发现了怎么办?
And what happens when they find out?
发现了 他们就会争论起来
They'll argue about what/to do with that information.
惹出纠纷可比领带更重要
The ties are less/important than the dissention.
我们还是得给他买点东西
We still have to buy him something.
他想得美
Not a chance.
我们不应该讨论这个 我们根本不应该知道
We weren't supposed to discuss/this.We're not supposed to know.
他还不应该把自己的名字写五次呢
He's not supposed to put his/name in there five times.
他想要礼物
He wants presents.
真可怜
It's sad.
是可悲
It's pathetic.
我还是去给他买个礼物吧
I'm still buying him a present.
不 不许买
No,you're not.
好吧
Fine!
怎么了?
What's wrong?
好象越来越糟糕了
I think it's getting worse.
我呼吸不了
I can't breathe.
快来个护士!
I need a nurse in here!
淋巴结阻塞了呼吸道
The lymph nodes/are cutting off her airway.
马上插管!
We've got to intubate!
Maggie的淋巴结肿大导致了呼吸道阻塞
The swollen lymph no were/cutting off maggie's airway.
使用酒精治疗后 已经可以自主呼吸
We shrunk 'em with alcohol.She's/breathing on her own now.
真是没劲
That sucks.
保存了4,300封邮件
4,300 saved emails,
没一个词与女同志 情夫或者小弟弟有关
and not a single mention of/"lesbionic," "sanchez," or "man-gina."
淋巴结肿大说明与心理因素无关
Swollen lymph nodes means/it wasn't psychological.
那是谁送的?
Who's that from?
圣诞老人啊
Santa,obviously.
谁都知道我崇拜他
'Cause you know I worship him.
哦不对 是撒旦
No,wait,I mean satan.
我老是分不清这俩
I always get 'em confused.
什么叫...阿尔卑斯蝴蝶结?
What is an alpine butterfly?
她为什么想学这个?
And why is she learning how to do one?
House 我们已经有了完整的病历史
House,we already have a full history.
- 你没必要再浪费.../- 登山绳的打结方法
- You don't need to waste time.../- it's just a climbing knot.
学那个有什么用?
But what does she use it for?
试试搜索捆绑
Try bondage.
试过了
I did once.
我被个女人绑起来过/还听她抱怨当院长有多艰辛
She just tied me down and whined about/how hard it is to be dean of medicine.
健身房不够卫生
Gyms aren't exactly pristine.
可能是真菌感染...到底谁送的啊?
Could be a fungal/infection.Seriously,who's it from?
没有发热 白细胞数量也正常
No fever,no elevated white count.
啊!
Ah!
好好玩
That's funny.
她的朋友给她发加菲猫动画
Her friend sent her a garfield cartoon.
那只猫果然是很喜欢吃千层面啊
That cat sure does love lasagna.
House!
别再玩了
Stop obsessing.
要不是因为我贪玩
If it weren't for my obsessions,
你们就不会知道她得了结节病
you wouldn't know that/she has sarcoidosis.
十八个月前 她把登山健身机给卖了
18 months ago she sold her stairmaster.
只用了两个月而已
It was only two months old.
如果她不是急需用钱
Now,either she needed the cash,
就说明她爬楼越来越吃力了
or climbing stairs was/getting more difficult.
十二个月前 她取消了一次徒步旅行
12 months ago,she/canceled a hiking trip.
如果她不是想躺在家里看电视
Now,either she just wanted/to sit home and watch tv,
就说明她连走路也吃不消了
or walking was getting more difficult.
她过去两年中一直都有关节疼痛
She's been suffering joint/pain for the last two years.
不信就瞧瞧看 要是你懂我的意思
Pull my ribbon,if you know what I mean.
结节病的血管紧张素转换酶水平/不应该这么低
A.C.E.Levels are too low for sarcoidosis.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
也许现在是潜伏期
Could just be an inactive phase.
还没到圣诞节呢
It's not christmas yet.
我知道 我不信撒旦 我是德鲁伊教的/(古凯尔特人之宗教)
I remembered I'm not/a satanist,I'm a druid.
肺部没有病变
No lung involvement.
暂时而已
Yet.
那得做支气管肺泡灌洗以确认
We'll need a bronchoalveolar lavage/to confirm it.
真可惜 我还打算给她一个圣诞惊喜呢
That's a shame... I was gonna/surprise her with one forhristmas.
哇!
Wow!
这个玩意肯定不止二十五块钱
Now,either that cost more than 25 bucks
否则我该怀疑苹果公司的市场策略了
or I'm seriously starting to doubt/steve jobs' business strategies.
谢啦!
But thanks!
最后一支生理盐水 Maggie
Last round of saline,maggie.
再深呼吸一下
One more big breath.
必须保证盐水能达到你的肺部 明白吗?
We've gotta get the liquid to go/all the way into your lungs,okay?
开始了
Here we go.
可能是某个病人送的
The gift could be from a patient.
送错了医生?
Who sent it to the wrong doctor?
很明显是House自己买来的
House obviously gave/the present to himself.
他们已经开始吵了
They're arguing right now.
我一早上都在找这个
I've been looking for this all morning.
你没去我桌上那个盒子里看看?
Did you look in the box on my desk?
对了 你妈打电话来
Oh,by the way,your mom called.
你爸去世了
Your dad's dead.
你就这么把礼物放在桌子上?
You left the present/sitting on your desk?
要是藏在我家衣橱里就没这个效果了
It wouldn't have been as effective/sitting in a closet in my home.
他们知道是你自己放的
They're gonna know it's from you.
不 他们会猜测是我放的
No,they're gonna guess/that it was from me.
甚至有九成的把握确定就是我放的
Might even be 90%/sure that it was from me,
但还说明 他们还有一成不确定/...是不是有内鬼在耍他们
but all that means is they're 10% sure that/one of the other guys is screwing them over.
你有没有考虑过 运用这份精力去...
Have you ever considered channeling/your powers to,
为中东和平而奋斗?
I don't know,bring/peace to the mid-east?
我做不来那个
I couldn't do that.
但如果中东和平 你可以去搞破坏?
But if they ever got/it,you could screw it up?
对 那才更像是我的本事
Yeah,that's more where my powers lie.
可能是Wilson送的
Gift could be from wilson.
是House啦
It's house.
你为什么总觉得是他在投机倒把?
Why do you have a/problem with him speculating?
因为他希望我们也相互猜忌
Because that's what house wants us to do.
肺部很干净
Lungs are pristine.
没有浸润或肺泡出血现象
No infiltrates or alveolar hemorrhage.
Maggie 我会把管子抽出来
Maggie,I'm gonna remove the scope.
你得咳嗽 明白吗
I need you to cough for me,okay?
用点力
A little harder.
很好
Great.
Maggie 睁开眼睛
Maggie,open your eyes.
你们怎么都不说话?
Why aren't you saying anything?
怎么了?
What's wrong?
Maggie的结节病检测是阴性
Maggie tested negative for sarcoidosis.
但她的眼睛开始出血
But she's bleeding into her eyes now.
血小板下降了吗?
Have her platelets dropped?
大幅下降
Plummeted.
最新读数显示还不到40
New labs show they're under 40.
再查不出病因 她各处都会开始出血
She'll bleed out of every orifice/if we don't find the cause.
可能是脾脏隔离 肺结核...
could be splenic/sequestration,tuberculosis...
高雪氏病 血栓性血小板低下症...
gaucher disease,ttp...
溶血性尿毒症综合征 败血症...
hemolytic uremic syndrome,sepsis...
如果没本事按字母倒序排列出来/就不要罗嗦这么多病因
listing all the possible causesis only/impressive if you can do it reverse-alphabetically.
我们得找出血小板下降的原因
We need to know why her/platelet machine is broken.
从造血源头着手
Go to the factory.
去做骨髓穿刺
Do a bone marrow aspiration.
我是你的神秘圣诞老人
I'm your secret santa.
你不该说出来的
You're not supposed to tell.
可你已经收到礼物了
But you got a present already.
说明你的神秘圣诞老人不止一个
Which means you have more/than one secret santa.
也许其他人也想让我开心呢
Or somebody else wants to make me happy.
圣诞快乐
Merry christmas.
亲爱的 让我修剪
Baby,I wanna trim your
baby,I wanna trim your
亲爱的 让我修剪
你美丽的圣诞树
beautiful christmas tree
本来呢 你应该躺床上的
one hand,you should be in bed.
可是我又让你去休息
And on the other/hand,I told you to rest.
你还真是为难啊
So I see your dilemma.
我觉得休息不是办法
I don't think resting is the problem.
链球菌会导致这个吗?
Can strep cause this?
快把衣服盖上...
Clap on...
我一发现就来这了
trust me,first place I went.
阴唇处没有皮疹
No rash on my labia.
你要检查一下吗?
Do you need to take a look?
我的钱还得留着去买Red Ryder的BB枪
I'm saving my money for/a red ryder bb gun.
换了深色的口红?
Darker shade of lipstick?
我没涂口红
I'm not wearing any.
你妈知道你是干什么的吗?
You tell your mother what you do?
不说也行
It doesn't matter.
好奇而已
I'm curious.
我可不想为了自己心安 去伤她的心
I don't need to break her/heart just so I can feel righteous.
你有跟驴子性爱表演吗?
Do you do a donkey show?
不是好奇
I'm not curious.
这很重要
It matters.
驴子还是骡子...
It's a donkey or a mule.
我老是不记得
I can never remember.
哇...
Wow...
笑得很诡异啊
that is a creepy smile.
我敢说那只驴子更诡异
I bet the donkey's is even creepier.
我需要解释吗?
Do I have to explain?
免了
Nope.
那是我的工作
That's my job.
接触传染性脓疱症
Contagious ecthyma.
任何接触都可能导致皮疹/流感症状及咽喉痛
Any contact can cause/rashes,flu symptoms,sore throat.
你有过...
Has there been...
...接触吗?
contact?
涂一点抗菌素膏 再给驴子戴上套套
Okay,antibiotic cream for/you,and a love glove for francis.
你俩都会好起来
You'll both be fine.
你来看看我的演出
You should come see the show.
我想你会喜欢的
I think you'd like it.
对不起 不喜欢西部片
Sorry,I hate westerns.
她们真的从没撒过谎?
so they really never lie?
看来你不太赞同
doesn't seem like it.
肃然起敬啊
Admirable.
你对Cameron也从不隐瞒吗?
You tell cameron everything?
不是的
No.
你觉得她有秘密吗?
you think she keeps secrets?
要是我知道 那就不是秘密了
If I knew,they wouldn't be secrets.
我希望她有
I hope she does.
人人都应该有点隐私权/即便是面对所爱的人
People have a right to a little/privacy,even from the people they love.
你给House买礼物了?
You buy house a present?
我犯得着吗?
Why would I?
为了给我添乱
To screw with me.
那我就要说"是"了
Then I'm gonna say yes.
慢着 慢着 停下
Wait,wait,stop,stop.
那是什么气味?
What's that smell?
骨头在冒烟
The bone is smoking.
她的骨头比钻头还硬?
Her bones are harder than the drill?
做了全身骨扫描/想找出臀骨变硬的原因
We ran a full-body bone scan to find/the cause of hardening in the hip.
没有热点区
No hot spots anywhere.
示踪剂有可能没激活
Tracer could have been inactive.
所以我搞砸了测试?
So I screwed up the test?
有许多可能
there are so many ways that/could have happened.
示踪剂也许没激活 也许没有彻底循环
Maybe it was inactive.Maybe/it didn't fully circulate.
循环了 摄像机采集到...
It circulated.The camera picked up...
嘿 嘿 这可是圣诞节
hey,hey...it's christmas.
你们还斗来斗去?
Why are you guys fighting?
为什么你会觉得没有"热点”区?
Why do you think there are no hot spots?
我没有搞砸
I did not screw up.
密度都一致
The density's consistent.
只意味着密度一致
It just means the density was consistent.
不说明这是"冷点"
It doesn't mean it was cold.
有可能她全身都是热点区
It's possible all she has are hot spots.
一致是因为她全副骨骼都在变成石头
It's consistent because her/entire skeleton is turning to stone.
这对满怀野心的超级英雄是好事
Good for an aspiring superhero.
对想要活着撑到"宽扎节"的人却是致命的/(非裔美国人节日 圣诞节后一周)
Fatal for a human hoping to/make it to kwanzaa.
应该是碳酸酐酶II型缺乏/(会造成骨质石化症)
it's gotta be from a/carbonicanhydrase type-ii deficiency.
它有自由意志.../它想是什么就是什么
It has free will...it doesn't have/to be anything it doesn't want to be.
我是说 如果不是碳酸酐酶II...
I meant,if it's not ca-2...
其它病因的骨质石化症都是不治之症
well,none of the other causes of/osteopetrosis are treatable.
你是对的 就只能是它了
You're right. It's gotta be.
检测她的血液/希望你的阳光乐观主义没用错地方
we'll run her blood  and hope that/your sunny optimism isn't misplaced.
他们指责kutner搞砸了测试 因为他们恨他
They accused kutner of screwing/up a test because they hate him.
你很吃惊吗?
You're surprised?
你出手搞鬼时 就会发生这种烂事
That's the sort of crap that happens/when you mess with people's heads.
总有一天他会搞砸一项测试
One day he will screw up a test.
如果他们因为喜欢他而不加指责/有人会因此而死
If they don't accuse him of that/because they like him,someone could die.
我们这是要去哪?
Where are we going?
哪也不去 我知道走路会让你腿疼
Nowhere,I just know it hurts you.
碳酸酐酶II缺乏症是蛋白质失调的遗传病
ca-2 deficiency's a genetic/disorder that scrambles proteins.
如果血液测试是阳性 你会需要骨髓移植
If the blood testis positive,you'll/need a bone marrow transplant.
移植像是希望微乎其微的委婉说法
Transplant sounds like a/euphemism for slim odds.
希望渺茫 但不是没有
Uh,slim but not none.
我们会检测Jane是否匹配
We're gonna need to/test jane for a match.
你们不是有捐献库么?
Don't you have donor banks?
Jane最有可能与你匹配
Jane is your best bet.
过程是绝对安全的 没有风险
The procedure's perfectly/safe.There's no risk.
没有风险!
No risk!
- 任何手术都.../- 那么就别跟我说什么无风险
- Any surgery has.../- then don't tell me there's no risk.
你是不是还要告诉我是无痛的?
You gonna tell me there's no pain either?
- 测试会有一点疼.../- 我不会有事的
- The testing will hurt a little.../- I'll be fine.
如果她没做这测试 你又没撑过去的话
If she doesn't do/this and you don't make it,
她整个余生都将自责的
she's gonna spend the rest/of her life blaming herself.
妈妈...
Mom...
求你
please.
找别人吧
Find someone else.
让别人去冒这个险
Let someone else take the risk.
捐献库查到克利夫兰有个49岁的男人/6个HLA抗原点有5个匹配
Donor bank turned up a 49-year-old man in/cleveland  who's a five out of six hla match.
克利夫兰起飞的第一班飞机是...
First flight out of/cleveland leaves at...
为什么一个49岁的克利夫兰男人/会比她女儿更匹配?
why is a 49-year-old cleveland man/a closer match than her daughter?
他也许不是 但Maggie不让测试她女儿
He may not be.Maggie/didn't let us test her.
为什么不?
Why not?
疼痛 危险 风险...
Pain,danger,risk of...
给出多个理由的唯一理由是/你在找别人想听的那个理由
the only reason to give multiple reasons is/your searching for what the person wants to hear.
House
House.
你看错了那个神圣的母亲
You were wrong about sainted mommy.
无所谓 你们可以忘掉捐献库了
Don't care.You can/forget the donor bank.
她没有碳酸酐酶II缺乏症
There's no ca-2 deciency.
我们能做的最多是让她舒服些
Best we can do is make her comfortable.
那是Taub给的吗?
Is that from taub?
是的
Yes.
没错 就是
Yes,it is.
圣诞快乐
Merry christmaS.
谁来告诉病人 她快死了?
Who's gonna tell the patient she's dying?
我来
I will.
我们找出她的病因前 谁都不准离开
And nobody leaves here until we/find out what killed her.
不管她有什么病 都是致命的
Whatever she has is fatal.
不管是58号还是907号病 都没什么区别
Makes no difference if it's/disease number 58 or 907.
你们生我的气?
You guys mad at me?
没有
Nope.
你别无选择
You had no choice.
我当然有选择
Of course I had a choice.
我作出选择 你们就别无选择了
you had no choice once I made my choice.
现在我选择不生你的气
And now I'm choosing not/to be mad at you.
为什么?
Why?
因为那会使House抓狂的
'Cause it'll drive house nuts.
那样你的生活会更好还是更糟?
You think that'll make/your lives better or worse?
我告诉妈妈 我才不管她怎么想
I told my mom I don't/care what she thinks.
我要你们测试我的骨髓
Want you to test my marrow.
我不能死
I can't be dying.
你当然能
Sure,you can.
你错了
You're wrong.
你甚至都不知道我有什么病
You don't even know what I have.
你有的是 和你女儿共度最后一个圣诞节
What you have is one last/christmas with your daughter.
最后的机会送她一个礼物...
One last chance to give her a present...
真相
the truth.
那不贵
It's inexpensive.
却很有价值
Highly valued.
不需要在圣诞节后排队退货
Never have to stand in line to/return it the day after christmas.
你说的是什么?
What are you talking about?
濒死的母亲不会因为疼而拒绝捐献测试
A mother who's going to die doesn't/refuse a donor test because it might hurt.
她拒绝 因为她知道根本不会匹配
She refuses when she/knows it won't match.
当母女不是真正的母女时 就可能发生
Which tends to happen when mother and/daughter aren't mother and daughter.
如果你宁愿继续骗我 我可以做DNA测试
I can do dna tests if you'd/rather keep lying to me.
我从没想过要孩子
I never wanted kids.
我爱孩子 但我的基因...
I love them,but with my genes...
我认识这样一个女人
I knew this woman.
瘾君子
A drug addict.
她怀孕了 不想堕胎
She got pregnant,didn't/want to have an abortion.
也希望女儿不知道亲生母亲是谁
But she also didn't want her daughter/to ever know who her real mother was.
是什么样的人
What she was.
我答应她绝不说
I promised never to tell.
对瘾君子守信比对你女儿守信更重要?
Then a promise to an addict is worth/more than a promise to your daughter?
告诉她太残忍了
It'd be cruel to tell her.
没错
Right.
她活在一个谎言里 你到死都是伪君子
She lives a lie,you/get to die a hypocrite.
妈妈 医生告诉我发生什么了
Mom,the doctors told me what's happening.
会没事的 甜心
it's gonna be okay,sweetheart.
我保证
I promise you.
医生有可能错了
Doctors can be wrong.
我还有机会...
There's still a chance I can beat...
你真的相信吗?
do you really believe that?
我信
I do.
不 妈妈 你快死了
No,mom,you're dying.
没人能帮你
Nobody can help you.
不会好起来的
It's not going to be okay.
真残酷
That was cold.
是啊
Yeah.
圣诞节你收了什么礼物?
What'd you get for christmas?
一块手表 一张vintage唱片/和第二版的柯南·道尔的书
I got a watch,a vintage lp,and/a second-edition conan doyle.
如果那还不算糟的话 我的病人快死了
And if that wasn't bad/enough,my patient's dying.
圣诞节死在医院里/没什么比这更压抑的了
Oh,christmas deaths in a hospital.../there's nothing more depressing.
没人愿意去病人房间
No one ever wants to/go in the patient's room.
就连志愿看护者都躲去一边
Even the candy stripers leave them alone.
但我看到些神奇的事
But I saw something amazing.
纯粹的真相
Pure truth.
她告诉她妈妈就快死了
She told her mother that she was dying.
剥夺了她所有的希望
Stripped her of all hope.
那听起来...
That sounds...
好恐怖
horrible.
就像看着你知道再也不会见到的天文奇观
It was like watching some bizarre astronomical/event that you know you're never gonna see again.
你总是告诉人们冷酷又难以接受的真相
You tell people the/cold,hard truth all the time.
你全身而退
You get off on it.
因为我不在意
'Cause I don't care.
她在意
She cared.
她还是那么做了
She did it anyway.
她那么做是因为她在乎
She did it because she cared.
圣诞精灵终于给了House一样/他欣赏的礼物
The angels of christmas have finally/given house a present he can appreciate.
别毁了它
Well,don't ruin it.
别把这算到耶稣身上
Don't pin this on christ.
他身上已经有够多钉子了
He's got enough nails in him.
- 病人不得不死.../- 你能不能脱了那帽子
- The patient had to die.../- would you take off that hat.
现在可是圣诞节
It's christmas.
这可是驯鹿
It's a reindeer.
这是驼鹿角在一个犹太人头上
It's a moose on a jew.
谁在意?
Who cares?
东西都有自己的位置
Things have their place.
你不会在圣诞树上挂四角铃
You wouldn't hang/dreidels from a christmas tree.
你可以
You could.
东西又不会在意
Things don't care.
是啊 它们不在意
No,they don't.
冬至日快乐 House
Happy solstice,house.
上帝让你们快乐休息 先生们
god rest ye merry,gentlemen
让你们无法沮丧
let nothing you dismay
记得我们的圣人耶稣 生于圣诞日
remember christ our savior/was born on christmas day
当我们迷途时/用撒旦的力量将我们挽救
to save us all from satan's power/when we were gone astray...
你们都没有节日精神么?
don't you people know holiday spirit?
但给我欢乐的蛋酒(利口酒的一种)
Bring me the eggnog of good cheer.
House 如果你要说什么 直接说
House,if you have something/to say,say it.
如果没什么要说/让我们在圣诞老人到之前回家
If you don't,give us a/chance to get home before santa.
吝啬鬼
Scrooge.
给病人维思通
Give the patient risperidone.
那是抗精神失常药 她快死了
That's an anti-psychotic.She's dying.
可是没疯
She's not crazy.
我就要上演圣诞奇迹了
I am going to perform a/christmas miracle.
哦 宽慰又欢乐的消息 宽慰又欢乐
Oh,tidings  of comfort/and joy  comfort and joy...
你说过骨质石化症的其他病因都是致命的
you said all the other causesof/osteopetrosis are fatal.
除了我们早先没想到的一个解释
Except for the one we discounted early.
因为那时是不可能的
Because it was impossible.
当胎儿形成 它只是一堆细胞
When a fetus forms,it's/just a mass of cells.
乳腺组织覆盖了身体的很大一部分
Breast tissue covers an/extensive portion of the body.
胎儿发育 大部分乳腺组织后退
As the fetus develops,most/of this tissue recedes,
只在有意思的地方余留
remaining only in the fun places.
但有时多余的乳腺组织/停留在不合时宜的地方
But sometimes extra breast tissue  is left/behind in places where it doesn't belong.
维思通可以有很多作用
Risperidone does a lot of things.
其中一个就是让乳腺组织肿胀/这样乳腺组织就更容易被找到
One is it makes breast tissue/swell,so we can find it more easily.
你是说我可能有乳腺癌...
You're telling me I could/have breast cancer...
在我乳房之外的某个地方? 这没道理
somewhere not in my/breasts?That doesn't make sense.
Taub的父母在Florida有间过冬公寓/他们仍然是纽约客
Taub's parents have a winter condo in/florida,but they're still new yorkers.
- 事实上 我爸妈.../- 无所谓
- Actually,my parents.../- don't care.
我只是打个比方
I told a parable.
现在我要起死回生了
Now I'm going to raise the dead.
给我注射器
Give me that syringe.
那可能是脂肪沉积
That's gotta be a fat deposit.
是的 我有可能错了
Yes,I could be wrong.
如果我错了 她就死定了
If i am,she's dead.
所以闭嘴吧
So shut up.
那是什么?
What's that?
维思通也引起乳漏
Risperidone also causes galactorrhea.
那是什么... 乳...乳汁?
What's that... galac...galactic?
张开嘴
Open your mouth.
放松 你以前尝过的
Relax,you've had it before.
我不是...
I am not...
奶?
milk?
呦!
Eww!
我们会切除你妈妈的肿瘤 给她化疗
We'll cut out your mom's/tumor and start her on chemo.
你其他的症状也会消失
All the rest of your/symptoms should go away.
我爱你
I love you.
我知道
I know.
祝你有美好人生
Have a wonderful life.
是谁将圣诞欢乐偷走
Mmm-mmm-mmm   who took the/merry out of christmas   whoa-o-oa
全世界的人都忘记了欢乐
people all over the/world forgot about merry
忙着打仗
too busy fightin' wars
忙着去火星
tryin' to make it to mars
想寻找光明 却找不到启明星
searchin' for light and can't/seem to find the right star oh ho
searchin' for light and/can't seem to findthe right star
是谁将圣诞欢乐偷走
who took the merry out/of christmas?Ye-eah
全世界的人都忘记了欢乐
people all over the/world forgot about merry
忙着买礼物/忙着读圣诞老人的趣味故事
too busy buyin' toys/learnin' 'bout santa's joys
是谁将圣诞欢乐偷走
who took the merry out of christmas?
快告诉我 是谁将圣诞欢乐偷走
Tell me now,y'all who took/the merry out of christmas?